1) Exceptions - should be handled?
2) Main mem cycles? If bus is 64 bit and block size is 32 - do we get 100 clock cycles or 101?
3) Memory is not stored in bytes (but integers.. because python doesn't have bytes, just aliases for strings).
4) No miss time for l1, l2 caches?



TODO:
-----

- align addresses to 4 (e.g: 127 -> 0), or middle of blocks (mainmemory can write in load / store to addresses that span multiple blocks, e.g: 0x0007 block size 4)
- take care of bus size for both r/w directions!




new questions:
--------------------
1) What if we have a write miss and L2 block size s > L1 block size?
We crop some of the block?
Is L2 block always > L1 block?

2) After write miss - do we flush only the old block to the next level or the new one as well? (in that case, dirty bit should be on almost always)

3) Miss rate - is (read hits + write hits) / (read hits + misses + write hits + misses)?

4) When there is no L2 cache, should the global MR be the same as L1?

5) When calculating AMAT - if extra cycles are required when the bandwidth between MM and cache is too small, should we account for them as well?

6) When we transfer data too big for the bus, do we count only the block size we have to transfer, or do we count the address bits as well?

7) Is it legal to ask for addresses in the middle of the block? (E.g: block size is 4 for L1 cache, and we ask for address 0x5, or block size is 8 and we ask for address 0xA)

8) Should we flush dirty blocks from cache to the memory by the end of the simulation?

9) flushing a block, do we pay 100 cycles for the main memory penalty + 1 more cycle for writing the new block (meaning, do we assume L1cache waits until MM is done writing the block before writing his new value)?

10) If L1 cache requests a block size of 4 and L2 cache only knows how to read block size of 8, are only 4 bytes returned on the bus? (this is important in order to calculate the cycles elapsed).

-----

11) If block_size is 4 bytes and we write data of 4 bytes to L1 cache and the block isn't there but it's not dirty or invalid, do we still perform a read from L2 cache? (this is meaningless as everything will get overriden anyway so we can optimize, but for the general case of block size larger than 4 we do that anyway).

12) Offset bits should include 2 bits of alignment or can we ignore them and get more bits for the tag instead?

TODO:
--------------------
- Change MM to 16MB


מקרי בדיקה:
============

נכונות -
1) כתיבה לכתובת 0
2) כתיבה לכתובת אחרונה בRAM (FFFFFF)
3) כתיבה לכתובת באמצע הבלוק (למשל: בלוק בגודל 8, כתובת באמצע הבלוק)
4) קריאה מכתובת שלא אתחלנו בMEM IN (מאותחלת ל0)
5) כתיבה לבלוק חדש בקאש 1,2 (INVALID)
6) קריאה של בלוק חדש שלא נמצא בקאש 1,2
7) קריאה של בלוק שנמצא בקאש 1
8) קריאה של בלוק שלא נמצא בקאש 1 אבל כן נמצא ב2
9) קריאה של בלוק שלא נמצא בקאש 1 אבל טאג עם מס' בלוק מתאים נמצא בקאש 1 (יתרחש FLUSH)
10) קריאה של בלוק שלא נמצא בקאש 1, לא נמצא בקאש 2 אבל טאג עם מס' בלוק מתאים נמצא בקאש 2 (יתרחש FLUSH)
11) כתיבה של בלוק שלא נמצא בקאש 1 אבל טאג עם מס' בלוק מתאים נמצא בקאש 1 (יתרחש FLUSH)
12) כתיבה של בלוק שלא נמצא בקאש 1, לא נמצא בקאש 2 אבל טאג עם מס' בלוק מתאים נמצא בקאש 2 (יתרחש FLUSH)

זמן ריצה במחזורים - 
1) בדיקה לכמה גדלי בלוקים - לראות שסופרים נכון את האקסטרה מידע שעובר על הBUS.
2) לבדוק את המקרים שבהם יש כתיבה כפולה (בלוק ישן שעובר FLUSH כשבכלל עשו WRITE לבלוק אחר).
3) לבדוק את המקרים שבהם יש קריאה, ואז MISS, ואז מביאים בלוק חדש מהרמה הבאה אבל הוא גורם לפינוי של בלוק ישן שעובר FLUSH

AMAT - 
1) לבדוק שהחישוב נכון לכל המקרי בדיקה שלמעלה - לוודא שמבדילים בין COMPULSARY MISS לבין CONFLICT.. גדליה כתב על זה במייל שצריך להסתכל בתרגול 3 עמוד 13, יש שם איזה טריק עם הנוסחאות..

עוד דברים -
לוודא שעבור 2 רמות קאש שהקבצי OUTPUT נכונים, בפרט הסטטיסטיקות